Guide to the Irish Immigration Reform Movement, New York Chapter Records AIA.016
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Irish Immigration Reform Movement, New York Chapter Records
1984-2007
1987-1991
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Irish Immigration Reform Movement
AIA.016
17 Linear Feet in 16 record cartons and 2 manuscript boxes.
The Irish Immigration Reform Movement (IIRM) was a grassroots organization established in 1987 whose primary objective was to legalize the status of undocumented immigrants from Ireland and 34 other countries adversely affected by America's 1965 Immigration Act. Working for legislative reform, the IIRM grew from a small New York-based group to a national organization with branches from Boston to San Francisco. The Irish Immigration Reform Movement (IIRM) records chronicle its activities on behalf of undocumented Irish immigrants between 1987 and 1990. The collection also includes materials related to the 1988 establishment of its sister organization, the Emerald Isle Immigration Center (EIIC), and to that organization's work meeting the day-to-day needs of immigrants through 2007.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically. Collection is arranged into six series:
I. Administration II. Fundraising III. Legislation IV. Lobbying V. Publications VI. Nonprint materials
Folders are arranged alphabetically. Collection is arranged into six series:
Missing Title
I. Administration, 1985-2003
II. Fundraising, 1987-1993
III. Legislation, 1986-1990
IV. Lobbying, 1984-1997
V. Publications, 1978-2000
VI. Nonprint materials, 1986-2007
Historical/Biographical Note
The Irish Immigration Reform Movement (IIRM) was a grassroots organization established in 1987 whose primary objective was to legalize the status of undocumented immigrants from Ireland and 34 other countries adversely affected by America's 1965 Immigration Act. The IIRM ceased activities in 1992.
Working for legislative reform, the IIRM grew from a small New York-based group to a national organization with branches in Boston, Chicago, Philadelphia, Houston, Washington, Kansas City, San Francisco and San Jose. Combining traditional grassroots activism with inside-the-beltway lobbying, the IIRM leveraged Irish-American political influence to help shape U.S. immigration policy in the late 1980s and in the process energized the Irish-American political presence in Washington.
The Immigration Act of 1990 (H.R. 4300) stands as the primary legislative legacy of the IIRM. This legislation provided a three-year transitional visa program through which 48,000 visas were granted to Ireland, as well as the annual diversity visa lottery program which continued into the twenty-first century.
Reflecting the IIRM's "all-Ireland" perspective, the transitional visa program contained a provision defining Northern Ireland as a separate state. This unique element, secured through intensive lobbying by the IIRM, enabled thousands from Northern Ireland to participate in the visa lottery who, prior to this, had been ineligible because the United States' immigration system classified them as English.
The IIRM was also instrumental in securing 25,000 visas for Ireland through several extensions of the Donnelly Visa program from 1988 up to the implementation of the Immigration Act of 1990.
In order to address the day-to-day problems of documented as well as undocumented Irish at that time, IIRM members established the Emerald Isle Immigration Center (EIIC), which since 1988 has served as a model for similar advice and advocacy agencies in the United States. It operates New York City offices in Woodside, Queens and in Woodlawn, the Bronx.
Scope and Content Note
The Irish Immigration Reform Movement (IIRM) records chronicle its activities on behalf of undocumented Irish immigrants between 1987 and 1990. The collection also includes materials related to the 1988 establishment of its sister organization, the Emerald Isle Immigration Center (EIIC), and to that organization's work meeting the day-to-day needs of immigrants through 2007. The IIRM story unfolds through minutes, correspondence, petitions, flyers, legislative and lobbying materials, membership and financial records, publications, posters, photographs, clippings, and ephemera generated by the New York office and by branches across the country.
While its constituency was primarily "New Irish" who had emigrated in the 1980s, the IIRM papers document relationships with the previous generation of Irish immigrants as well as with the Irish-American community; see, for example, files on the Immigration Subcommittee of the Ancient Order of Hibernians and the Irish Immigration Working Committee as well as many of the organizations represented in Series II: Fundraising. Among the correspondents are top Irish government officials like Charles J. Haughey (1925-2006) and Brian Lenihan (1930-1995); and members of the U.S. Congress, including Edward M. Kennedy (D-MA), Bruce A. Morrision (D-CT), and Charles Schumer (D-NY).
In 1988 the IIRM hired the lobbying firm of Holt, Miller and Associates to assist them to plan and organize to bring their message before the United States Congress. They worked closely with its principal, Harris N. Miller, a veteran of the Immigration and Refugees Subcommittee staff of Ron Mazzoli (D-KY), who had given his name to the bill that created the Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986. A significant portion of this collection documents Miller's work on behalf of the IIRM in 1988 and 1989. In addition, there are extensive papers (including reference materials) relating to various House and Senate bills on immigration reform between 1986 and 1990, especially H.R. 4300 (Immigration Act of 1990). Of particular interest is Don Martin's testimony on Legal Immigration Reform to the U.S. House of Representatives Subcommittee on Immigration, Refugees, and International Law in September 1989 (Box 7, Folder 14); and the IIRM's "Case for Immigration Reform" presented to Joe Moakley (D-MA), Chairman on Rules, U.S. House of Representatives in 1990 (Box 12, Folder 22).
The Emerald Isle Immigration Center's work in the late 1980s – particularly its efforts to obtain bank accounts, driver's licenses, housing, medical insurance, education, and legal protection for undocumented immigrants – constitutes another large segment of the IIRM papers. EIIC records from 1990-2007 which were accessioned with the IIRM papers have remained integrated in Series I. Administration; the later years reflect services that include job-training and placement as well as citizenship and voter registration drives as a means to empowerment. In 1998 the EIIC presented President Bill Clinton with the Paul O'Dwyer Peace and Justice Award at a White House ceremony on September 11, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 9).
The efforts of key individuals on behalf of the IIRM and the EIIC are documented in Series I. in the files of Sean Minihane, Pat Hurley, Sean Benson, and Brian O'Dwyer as well as in the minutes of the Steering Committee and National Council which can be found in Series IV.
Among the historic publications included in this collection is "Tarnishing the Golden Door," the 1989 report of the New York City Commission on Human Rights.
Series VI. Nonprint Materials includes an IIRM public-service announcement made in September 1987 by entertainer Tommy Makem; a 24-minute video, "The New Irish in America: Living in the Shadows" made in 1987 by the IIRM; and two mini-DV cassettes recording the IIRM's 20th anniversary reunion event held at New York University in October 2007.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Related Archival Materials
The Ireland House Oral History Collection (AIA 030) includes interviews with Irish Immigration Reform leaders Sean Minihane, Patrick Hurley, Mae O'Driscoll, Sean Benson and Lisa Johnston, as well as with Fr. Colm Campbell, Patricia O'Callaghan, Adrian Flannelly, and Donald A. Kelly, who worked with the undocumented Irish during the 1980s.
Irish Immigration Reform Movement, Boston Chapter Records (AIA 073)
Custodial History
Gift of the Irish Immigration Reform Movement, 1997. The papers of the IIRM were housed in the offices of the Emerald Isle Immigration Center (EIIC) in the Woodside section of Queens, NY. They were surveyed there by Marion R. Casey and Katie Senft in June 2001. In December 2006 they were transferred by deed of gift to the Archives of Irish America at the Tamiment Library, New York University.
Immigrants -- United States -- Political activity -- History -- 20th century.; Immigrants -- United States; Irish Americans -- New York (State) -- New York -- Political activity.; Irish Americans |z New York (State) |z New York |x Politics and government.; Irish Americans -- New York (State) -- New York.; Emigration and immigration law -- United States.; Minihane, Sean; Miller, Harris N., 1954-; O'Dwyer, Brian; Emerald Isle Immigration Center; Haughey, Charles J.; Schumer, Charles E.; Lenihan, Brian P., 1930-; Kennedy, Edward M. (Edward Moore), 1932-2009; Benson, Sean; Morrison, Bruce A.
- I: Administration, 1985-2002; 217472
  - A: General Files, 1985-2002; 245422
    - Ancient Order of Hibernians, 1988-1989, undated; 217478 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ancient Order of Hibernians: Immigration Subcommittee - Divisions, 1989; 217479 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Background: Irish Immigration Reform Movement (IIRM) - Information Booklet, 1989; 217482 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Background: Irish Immigration Reform Movement; Immigration Reform, 1988-1989; 217481 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Background, Minutes, Correspondence, 1987; 217480 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Benson, Sean, 1990-1991; 217483 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Benson, Sean: Correspondence I, 1989-1994; 217484 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Benson, Sean: Correspondence II, 1989-1994; 217485 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Benson, Sean: Correspondence, 1990-1991; 234445 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Benson, Sean: Reports, Clippings, 1990-1991; 217486 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Constitution (IIRM), Nov 1987; 236752 (Box 1, Folder 10a)
    - Contacts: General, Media, undated; 217487 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Contacts: Ethnic Groups, 1987; 217488 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1987; 217489 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1988; 217490 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1989-1992; 217492 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: Honorary Advisory Council, 1987; 217491 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence: Inquiries, 1989; 217493 (Box 1, Drawer 17)
    - Dissolution: National Executive Committee of the IIRM, 1991; 233660 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Driver's Licenses, 1987; 217495 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Education, 1988-1989; 217515 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Emerald Isle Immigration Center (EIIC), 1997-2002; 217496 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Emerald Isle Immigration Center: Board of Directors, Correspondence, 1991; 235571 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Emerald Isle Immigration Center: Board of Directors, Report to, 1990; 217498 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Emerald Isle Immigration Center: Briscoe Awards, 1998-1999; 217500 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Emerald Isle Immigration Center: Business Report, 2001-2002; 217499 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Emerald Isle Immigration Center: Correspondence, 1989-1991; 217501 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Emerald Isle Immigration Center: Correspondence, 1990-1992; 217502 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Emerald Isle Immigration Center: Financial, 1988, 2000-2002; 217504 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Emerald Isle Immigration Research Center: Fundraising, 1990-1991; 217503 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Employment, 1987, undated; 217529 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Fitzgerald, Matthew, Rev., 1987-1988; 236789 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Forms; Logo: Originals, 1988-1991; 217506 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Forms; Stationery, 1988-1990; 217536 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - General Meetings: Minutes, 1987-1988; 217507 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - General Meetings: Minutes, 1989; 217508 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Health Insurance, 1990; 217509 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Hotline Call Reports, 1988-1989; 217510 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Hurley, Pat, 1988-1989; 217511 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Incorporation Papers, Documentation, 1987-1989; 217512 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Information Kits, 1987; 217513 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Lease (EIIC Offices), 1988-1993; 217514 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Legal Advice, 1987-1988; 217516 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Mail Issued, 1988; 217518 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Mail Issued, Jan 1989-Jul 1989; 217519 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Mail Issued, Oct 1989-Dec 1989; 217520 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Mail Issued, 1990; 217521 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Mailing Lists; Phone numbers, 1988; 217517 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Mailing: Postcard, circa 1990; 217522 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Minihane, Sean, 1987-1988; 235208 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Minihane, Sean (includes report on Delegation to Ireland), 1989; 217523 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Minihane, Sean: Correspondence, 1988-1989; 235572 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Minihane, Sean: Correspondence, 1990; 217526 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Minihane, Sean: Files I, 1989-1990; 217524 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Minihane, Sean: Files II, 1989-1990; 217525 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - New Ireland Association: Formation, By-Laws, 1990-1991; 217527 (Box 2, Drawer 24)
    - New Irish: Guidelines, Rights of Immigrants; Handbook for New Irish I, 1988; 217528 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - New Irish: Guidelines, Right of Immigrants, Handbook for New Irish II, 1988; 235206 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - O'Dywer, Brian, 1988-1991; 217537 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - O'Dwyer, Brian: Clippings on Immigration, 1988-1991; 217538 (Box 2, Drawer 28)
    - O'Dwyer, Brian: Correspondence, 1988-1995; 217541 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - O'Dwyer, Brian: Correspondence, Center for Immigration Reform, 1989-1990; 217539 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - O'Dwyer, Brian: Correspondence, Catholic Charities, 1988-1990; 217540 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - O'Dwyer, Brian: Collins v. New York City Health and Hospitals Corporation, 1991-1992; 217542 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - O'Dwyer, Brian: Education Issues, 1985, 1989; 217543 (Box 3, Drawer 5)
    - O'Dwyer, Brian: Immigration Law and Procedures, 1987-1990; 217544 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - O'Dwyer, Brian: Kennedy/Simpson/Simon Bill, 1989; 217545 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - O'Dwyer, Brian: Research, 1988-1989; 217546 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - O'Dwyer, Brian: Research Materials I, 1988-1992; 217547 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - O'Dwyer, Brian: Research Materials II, 1988-1992; 217548 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - O'Dwyer, Brian: Report City of New York Commission on Human Rights, "Tarnishing the Golden Door", Aug 1989; 217549 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - O'Dwyer, Brian: Speeches, 1990-1992, undated; 217550 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - O'Dwyer, Paul, 1987; 217551 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Office of Immigrant Affairs, Department of City Planning, City of New York, 1989-1990; 217552 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Petitions, Signed (see also Box 14 for remainder of signed petitions), circa 1988; 217553 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Police Departments, 1988; 217554 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Requests for Information (students), 1989; 217555 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Research, 1991-1992; 217556 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Solidarity Day, 1989; 217557 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Steering Committee, 1989-1990; 217561 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Steering Committee: Constitution; Members; Correspondence, 1990, undated; 217558 (Box 3, Drawer 21)
    - Steering Committee: Minutes, 1988; 217559 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Steering Committee: Minutes, Jan 1989-Jun 1989; 217560 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Surveys and Questionnaires, 1988-1990; 217562 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Tax Seminars, 1989; 217563 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - U.S. Chamber of Commerce, 1989; 217564 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Untitled Play Script, undated; 217565 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - B: Financial Records, 1987-1991; 217535
    - Advertising, 1990; 217531 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Check Registers, Aug 1987-Oct 1987; 217532 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Check Registers, Nov 1987-Jan 1988; 217533 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Corporate; Franchise Tax, 1988-1990; 217530 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Deposits, 1987; 217566 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Deposits, Jan 1989-Mar 1989; 217567 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Deposits, May 1989-Jun 1989; 217568 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Deposits, Jul 1989-Sep 1989; 217569 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Deposits, Oct 1989-Dec 1989; 217570 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Deposits, Jan 1990-Mar 1990; 217571 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Deposits, Apr 1990-Jun 1990; 217572 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Deposits, Jul 1990-Sep 1990; 217573 (Box 4, Drawer 4)
    - Deposits, Oct 1990-Dec 1990; 217574 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Deposits, 1991; 217575 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Expenses I, 1988; 217576 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Expenses II, 1988; 217577 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Expenses: Staff, General I, 1989; 217578 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Expenses: Staff, General II, 1989; 217579 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Expenses: Martin, Don, 1989; 217580 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Expenses: Minihane, Sean, 1988-1989; 217581 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Expenses: Minihane, Sean, 1990; 217582 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Expenses: O'Donnell, Sean, 1987; 217583 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Financial Statement as of December 31, 1990, Dec 1990; 217584 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Invoices: Paid, Jan 1990-Mar 1990; 217585 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Invoices: Paid, Apr 1990-Jun 1990; 217586 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - National Account, 1990; 217587 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Taxes, 1990-1991; 217588 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- II: Fundraising, 1987-1993; 217473
  - A. Funding Sources, 1987-1993; 245959
    - Allied Irish Bank, 1989; 217589 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - American Ireland Fund, 1988-1911; 217590 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - American Ireland Fund, 1998; 217591 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Apple Bank Grants Applications, 1991-1998; 217592 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Chase Bank, 1993; 217593 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Chemical Bank, 1993; 217594 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Citigrant (Citibank), 1988; 217595 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence; Solicitations, 1987-1992; 217596 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - East New York Savings Bank, 1992; 217597 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Emerald Society, 1989; 217598 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Emigrant Savings Bank, 1988-1992; 217599 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Equitable Life, 1992; 217600 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Fleet Bank, 1993; 217601 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Football Clubs, 1988; 217602 (Box 5, Drawer 6)
    - Friendly Sons of St. Patrick, 1990-1993; 217603 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Friends of Irish Immigration, 1990; 217604 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Grants Application Correspondence, 1990-1992; 217605 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Grants: General, 1987-1990; 217606 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Ideas, 1990; 217608 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Irish American Cultural Institute, 1991; 217607 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Irish Government, 1989; 217610 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Irish Institute, 1990-1991; 217611 (Box 5, Drawer 14)
    - J. P. Morgan, 1991-1994; 217614 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - John McEnroe Foundation, 1991; 217612 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Joyce Mertz-Gilmore Foundation, 1991; 217613 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Kelleher, Denis, 1992-1993; 217615 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Letter/Direct Mail Campaign, 1988; 217609 (Box 5, Drawer 19)
    - Manufacturer's Hanover Trust, 1988-1992; 217616 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - MCI Supports the Irish, 1990; 217617 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Mutual of New York, 1993; 217618 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - New York Community Trust, 1988-1991; 217619 (Box 5, Drawer 23)
    - New York Foundation, 1987-1991; 217620 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - New York State, 1989-1990; 217621 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Norstar Bank, 1992; 217622 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Opportunities; Applications, 1990-1993; 217623 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - St. Patrick's Day Activities, 1989-1990; 217624 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Smith Barney Employee Fund, 1992; 217625 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - United Irish Counties: Correspondence, 1987; 217626 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - B. Events, 1987-1993; 245960
    - Bar/Restaurant Lists, 1989-1990; 217627 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Contacts-Local, 1988-1993; 217628 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Dinner Dance I, 1989; 217629 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Dinner Dance II, 1989; 217630 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Dinner Dance I, 1990; 217631 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Dinner Dance II, 1990; 217632 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Dinner Dance, 1991; 217633 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Fun Run, 1990; 217634 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Fun Run, 1991; 217635 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - General Fundraising, 1993; 217636 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Mass of Hope, 1989; 217637 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - St. Patrick's Dance Committee Fundraising Proposal, 1989-1992; 236790 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - St. Patrick's Day Parade, 1988-1989; 217638 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Town Hall Foundation: Wolf Tones Concert, 1988; 217639 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Various, 1989-1991; 217640 (Box 5, Folder 45)
- III: Legislation, 1986-1990; 217474
  - 101st Congress: Committees, 1989; 217659 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 101st Congress: Members, 1989; 233237 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Ad Hoc Committee for Irish Affairs, 1990; 233238 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Members of Congress, 1988-1990; 217660 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Hearings: General, 1988-1989; 233242 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - House: Immigration Subcommittee, 1989; 233245 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Immigration Reform and Control Act - Amnesty, 1982-1989; 233240 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986 (IRCA), 217661 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Immigration Reform and Control Act (IRCA), 1986-1987; 217662 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - INS Legal Immigration Reform Bill, 1988-1989; 233243 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Legislation: Various, 1987, 1998; 217663 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Senate: Immigration Subcommittee, 1988; 233244 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - H.R. 1306: Gilman Bill [Representative Benjamin A. Gilman (NY)], 1987-1990; 217664 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - H.R. 1306: Gilman Bill Hearing, Sep 1989; 217665 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - H.R. 1306: Gilman Bill-Military Enlistment, 1989-1991; 217666 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - H.R. 2448: Correspondence; Rep. Hamilton Fish (NY), 1989; 217667 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - H.R. 2478: Donnelly Amendments, 1988; 217668 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - H.R. 2646: Rep. Lamar Smith (TX), 1989; 217669 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - H.R. 3374: Rep. Bruce Morrison (CT) I, 1989-1990; 217670 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - H.R. 3374: Rep. Bruce Morrison (CT) II, 1989-1990; 217671 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - H.R. 3511: Donnelly Bill 10st Congress, Rep. Brian Donnelly (D-Mass), 1989; 217672 (Box 6, Drawer 21)
  - H.R. 3916: Schumer Bill, Rep. Charles Schumer (D-NY), 1988; 217673 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - H.R. 4165: Schumer Bill, 1990; 217674 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - H.R. 4230: Engel Legislation, Rep. Elliot Engel (D-NY), 1988-1989; 217675 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - H.R. 4293: Rep. James Walsh (NY), 1998; 217676 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - H.R. 4300: Morrison Bill: Draft; Rep. Bruce Morrison (CT) Draft, Section by Section I, Feb 1990; 217677 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - H.R. 4300: Morrison Bill: Draft; Rep. Bruce Morrison (CT) Draft, Section by Section II, 1990; 217678 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - H.R. 4300: Morrison Bill: Draft, Final, March 14, 1990; 217689 (Box 6, Drawer 28)
  - H.R. 4300: Morrison Bill "Family Unity and Employment Opportunity Immigration Reform Act of 1990" (final version) I, Mar 19, 1990; 217690 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - H.R. 4300: Morrison Bill "Family Unity and Employment Opportunity Immigration Reform Act of 1990" (final version) II, Mar 19, 1990; 217692 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - H.R. 4300: Morrsion, Bruce, Amendment in the Nature of a Substitute, 1990; 217687 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - H.R. 4300: Morrison Bill, Analysis, 1990; 217679 (Box 6, Drawer 32)
  - H.R. 4300: Morrison Bill: Rep. Jack Brooks (TX), Chair Judiciary Committee, Phone Calls to, 1990; 217688 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - H.R. 4300: Committee Print, 1990; 217681 (Box 7, Folder 1)